

About me

"Give me a lever, a place to stand and well-done investigation, and I will move the earth." - Archimedes' semi-cit.

I was born as tireless curious. I'm a proactive guy, used to knowledge sharing and receiving feedbacks (whether positive or negative).

In my spare time I enjoy <u>capturing</u> the beauty around me, and deep dive in the world of personal finance.

Hard skills

- Debugging
- Requirements analysis
- Testbook management
- · Defect and bug management
- Reporting and KPIs
- User experience
- Manual and Automated tests
- No Regression and Acceptance tests

Soft skills

- Teamwork
- Problem Solving
- Adaptability
- Critical thinking
- Emotional Intelligence
- Time management

Used technologies

- Asana Figma Miro
- Datadog
- Typescript
- Postman, Cypress and WebdriverIO
- AWS Lambda + CloudWatch
- Play Console App Store Connect
- Jira and Confluence

Spoken languages

Italian - Mother tongue English - B2

ANTONIO SESSA

SENIOR QA ENGINEER ISTQB® Certified Tester - CTFL & CT-TAE PSM™ Scrum Master

in/antoniosessa

Milan, Italy

Experiences

Senior QA Engineer

₽ ProntoPro

ProntoPro S.r.l.

Jan 2024 - Present

- Currently **Senior Engineer S2**, accordingly to this <u>Career Path</u>
- Support Product and technical roadmaps definition
- Implementation of a **Company Status Page** to manage and monitor alerts
- Experience with working with highly scalable, maintainable code
- Development of a toolkit in Typescript to generate test scenarios, orchestrated in AWS Lambda and monitored via CloudWatch + Slack
- Experience with **GitHub Actions** and containerised environment (**Docker**)
- Dialogue with Customer Care and Customer Experience teams, to provide mitigations and report bugs to the Engineering team

QA Engineer

ProntoPro

ProntoPro S.r.l.

May 2022 - Dec 2023

- <u>Shift-Left</u> approach to ensure consistency and solidity of applications during new features design processes
- Active participation to backlog refining process
- · Validation and verification of new features developed
- Design and coding of an automated e2e test suite (Cypress/WebdriverIO)

QA Test Lead and Business Analyst at Sky Italia



Netcom Group S.p.a.

Jan 2017 - May 2022

- Monitoring a manual testers group
- Functional tests design and use cases development
- Activities cost estimation both man-days and equipment
- Process management, analysis and validation results export
- Exchanges with PO about final Customer Experience
- Verification and analysis management of Field Trial feedbacks
- Supporting Incident Management activities coming from Sky Go Real Customers

QA Test Engineer at Sky Italia



Netcom Group S.p.a.

Sep 2015 - Jan 2017

Certifications

ISTQB® Automation Engineer (CT-TAE) taken on 05/12/2023

ISTQB® Foundation Level (CTFL) taken on 25/07/2023

Professional Scrum Master I (PSM $^{\text{TM}}$ I) taken on 28/03/2020

First Certificate in English (FCE) - B2 level taken on 11/07/2015

Engineering practise License - A section taken on Sep 2015

Education

University of Salerno

2013 - 2015

Computer Engineering Master's Degree - Final grades 110/110

Master's Degree final exam:

"Graph matching algorithms for Social Network Analysis"